

New Delhi, India & California, USA prashant.khanduri@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/prashantkhanduri www.khanduri.com

Full stack generalist (expert Backend knowledge, functional Frontend skills) with over a decade of experience in building production grade web applications / systems. Core strengths are in building platforms, and have experience as team lead and managerial roles as well.

Professional Experience

CTO Sn126 | March 2018 - Present

- · Prevent failures in production environments by predicting and preempting software bugs before they are deployed to production.
- · Catch functional and performance regressions in backend services before your release process kicks in.
- · Various companies have adopted Diffy (https://github.com/opendiffy/diffy: our OSS offering) into their workflows and are benefiting from its automated

Engineering Manager Affirm, Inc. | July 2015 - March 2018

- Data platform EM: responsible for building Affirm's proprietary financial platform, as well as our real-time high-throughput data processing pipeline
- Build and maintain the bank authentication pipeline for pulling in account infromation
- · Architected the monitoring and alerting solution used by all internal platform teams

Senior Software Engineer Jawbone | April 2014 - July 2015

- Insights & Intelligence team: responsible for building an intelligent guide that helps our users make good health choices
- · Worked on building the Insights system and the internal CRM system to manage the insight content and building the Smart Coach brand

Generalist Software Engineer Hearsay Social | December 2012 - April 2014

- Designed and developed a notification platform
- · Worked on building the analytics and reporting framework

Software Development Engineer 2 Microsoft | January 2010 - December 2012

- Bing Relevance: responsible for ranking the top documents in Bing's algorithmic web search results (Top 100K queries)
- Developing new algorithms to extract ranking signals and features from petabytes of user browsing activity logs
- Using data mining and machine learning techniques to optimize user satisfaction metrics
- Windows Live: Implemented a service for syncing data from a system store to a DHCP server (for the server to hand out correct IP leases required for PXE booting)

Internships Various | 2003 - 2009

- Microsoft Corporation: Windows Live Mesh- May 2009 Aug 2009
- Created an assembly that provisioned a delegated authentication token management service
- Amazon.com Inc: Personalization Aug 2007 Dec 2007
- · Worked on a ranking mechanism to generate a tag set which describe the list recommended items
- Sun Microsystems: Complex Systems Group- Jan 2006 Apr 2006
- · Participated in the design and development of a simulation infrastructure for the behavioral analysis of wireless sensor networks
- Amazon.com Inc: Digital Media Technologies- May 2005 Aug 2005
- Worked on the variety of upgrades to the digital media pipeline (mainly the first internal REST client to the S3 service)
- Epson Canada: Barcode Recognition Jan 2004 Apr 2004
- Developed a universal 2D barcode decoding application for hand-held image-scanners







Education

MSc in Computer Science University of Southern California | 2008 - 2009





B.ASc.(Hons) in Computer Engineering University of Waterloo | 2003 - 2008

Key Skills

- Software Development, Web Services, Platform, APIs, Data pipelines
- · Python, Javascript, Java
- MySQL / Postgres, AWS, GCP
- Flask / Django, React (native)



